<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="3.9.0">Jekyll</generator><link href="https://sgibson91.github.io/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="https://sgibson91.github.io/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2021-01-29T12:21:51+00:00</updated><id>https://sgibson91.github.io/feed.xml</id><title type="html">Dr Sarah Gibson</title><subtitle>A collection of projects Sarah contributes to</subtitle><entry><title type="html">Continuous Integration: Fail Fast and Fail First</title><link href="https://sgibson91.github.io/blog/continuous-integration-fail-fast-fail-first/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Continuous Integration: Fail Fast and Fail First" /><published>2020-02-27T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2020-02-27T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>https://sgibson91.github.io/blog/continuous-integration-fail-fast-fail-first</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://sgibson91.github.io/blog/continuous-integration-fail-fast-fail-first/">&lt;p&gt;Sarah and Graham have different career backgrounds - Sarah having come through academia whereas Graham earned his stripes in industry. However in their current roles, they often find themselves using the same tools, for example Continuous Integration. They have written this blog post to identify how academia and industry may use Continuous Integration in different ways, and what they might learn from one another.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;what-is-continuous-integration-and-why-do-we-use-it&quot;&gt;What is Continuous Integration and why do we use it?&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In Continuous Integration (CI) and Continuous Deployment (CD), the key concept is “continuous”. That is where it departs from what software engineering teams were doing before: rather than &lt;em&gt;eventually&lt;/em&gt; integrating, at the end of developing a feature, we do it &lt;em&gt;continuously&lt;/em&gt;, as we’re working. Instead of &lt;em&gt;eventually&lt;/em&gt; deploying, when we’ve got a collection of features built and bugs fixed, we do it &lt;em&gt;continuously&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The tools we use for these activities help us integrate and deploy continuously. Our pipelines give code authors and reviewers information about the quality of their submission, and its readiness to go into our products.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;These tools also &lt;em&gt;hinder&lt;/em&gt; continuous integration and deployment. How? Generating that information takes time, so development is slowed down waiting for the build job, test run, or other pipeline task to complete.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;long-running-pipelines&quot;&gt;Long-Running Pipelines&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;People very rarely set out to create very long pipelines, they happen by accumulation. We set out to improve our test coverage, and the time spent running tests increases. With compiled languages like C++ or Java, our efficient, best-practice build system becomes slower as our projects gain features and complexity.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Sometimes, we find new tools that can benefit our workflow, and add them to the pipeline to provide automatic adoption. Code formatting tools, static analysis and advanced error detection systems, automatic documentation generators: they can all add value to our work by improving our code, but they all take time to run and that time comes at a price.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A long-running pipeline interrupts our mental flow. The longer it takes your tools to give you feedback, the more likely you are to go and read Slack, or check Twitter, or get up and make a coffee, while you’re waiting. Any of these activities disrupts your mental context and it’ll take time and effort to get back into doing your work.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Ideally - but probably impossibly - it’d be great to have a visual indication in your IDE, updating live, that everything is OK, or that there’s an issue. Imagine if as you typed, your Jupyter notebook ran your tests and showed a big tick or cross in the corner. As you edit your Pydoc comments, the API documentation on your Github page is changing to reflect your typing. As soon as you press save, a new version of your library appears on PyPI.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Unfortunately each of these activities actually takes time, so we need to make some choices. We want to find the sweet spot between gaining confidence in the software we’re writing, and keeping our pace and focus up.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;prioritise-failure&quot;&gt;Prioritise Failure&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If the goal of a CI or CD pipeline is to determine that a code change is a good candidate for integration or deployment, then it can finish as soon as it has determined that a change is &lt;em&gt;not&lt;/em&gt; a candidate. If a test fails, no amount of further inspection or analysis is going to make that test pass - the code needs changing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is “failing fast” - giving up as soon as you have indication that there’s a problem. Most workflow tools, including Github actions and Jenkins, will stop as soon as a step in the workflow fails. For example, they won’t run the unit tests if there’s an error in the build.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You can speed things up even further by stopping the test step as soon as any test fails, instead of gathering and reporting all test results. As an example, the popular &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;jest&lt;/code&gt; test runner for Javascript has a &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;--bail &amp;lt;n&amp;gt;&lt;/code&gt; option, which exits after &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;n&lt;/code&gt; test failures are detected. In the popular Python testing module &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;pytest&lt;/code&gt;, the equivalent is &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;--maxfail=n&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Making this change makes it faster to discover that &lt;em&gt;something&lt;/em&gt; is wrong, at a cost of not finding out &lt;em&gt;how much&lt;/em&gt; is wrong. In a way, this doesn’t really matter. Contributors should be encouraged to satisfy themselves of the quality of their work before submitting a pull request, so that the pipeline is only a backstop and not the first place they find out about problems.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;fail-first&quot;&gt;Fail First&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Another technique to speed up pipelines is to put the steps that cover the most &lt;em&gt;likely&lt;/em&gt; or &lt;em&gt;impactful&lt;/em&gt; failures first. If developers don’t tend to use a feature of your software, and therefore break it frequently without noticing, run the tests for that feature early in the pipeline. If a failure in a component would have a huge impact on users’ work, make sure to test that early.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This borrows from the electrical engineering concept of a “smoke test”. A quick test for problems in electrical equipment is to plug it in and check whether it starts smoking. If there’s no smoke, it doesn’t tell you that there’s &lt;em&gt;nothing&lt;/em&gt; wrong, but does suggest you can move on to more detailed inspection. If &lt;a href=&quot;http://catb.org/jargon/html/M/magic-smoke.html&quot;&gt;the magic smoke escapes&lt;/a&gt;, there’s no need to do any further testing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You can arrange to fail first without needing any test-ordering facility in your test runner. Create separate steps in the pipeline for the smoke tests and the wider test suite. If you can tell your test runner what directory or folder to find tests in, then you can organise your test files into separate suites.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Run the smoke tests first, and fail the pipeline if any of them doesn’t pass.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;come-back-later&quot;&gt;Come Back Later&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Maybe there’s information you need, but you don’t need it &lt;em&gt;now&lt;/em&gt;. One of us (Graham) worked in the Developer Efficiency group at Facebook, where hundreds of commits per day were being made by developers all over the world. If the continuous integration pipeline took too long on a patch, then the code would have changed out from under the patch author - Facebook use &lt;a href=&quot;https://trunkbaseddevelopment.com/&quot;&gt;trunk-based development&lt;/a&gt; so everybody is committing to &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;master&lt;/code&gt; - and they’d have to fix it to resubmit. Hardly continuous integration!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The pipeline that ran on commit only performed smoke tests and some basic analysis, and automatically merged the commit if these tests passed. Separately, a more complete (and longer-running) set of tests ran on a schedule.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If tests failed in the scheduled suite, how did we know what to do? The CI system automatically &lt;a href=&quot;https://git-scm.com/docs/git-bisect&quot;&gt;bisected&lt;/a&gt; the failure, using the previous run’s commit as the last known-good commit and its own as the first known-bad commit. Sometimes the failure couldn’t be isolated to a single commit because they were introduced by infrastructure problems, but often bisecting would identify a code change that caused the failure. When it does, an issue can be raised and assigned to the commit author to fix the problem.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;what-implications-does-this-have-for-continuous-analysis&quot;&gt;What implications does this have for Continuous Analysis?&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As the discussion around reproducibility in academia develops, many researchers are turning to software engineering practices, such as CI, to verify their results are reproducible as they develop their analysis code. The idea being that a Continuous Analysis (CA) pipeline will alert a researcher to a commit which changes the output of their code. They can then investigate whether this change is due to coding practices or a fundamental change in their model, and the implications of that new model.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But here we run into the same problem. As the models gain complexity, they become longer to run (sometimes taking months!) and perhaps require High Performance Computing (HPC) resources that are not available on most CI/CD platforms. So how can we break this down?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We should say that it is possible to run a job launched by CI on a HPC system, however it is not straightforward and often involves using secret variables.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;More often than not, it’s the model generation or simulation scripts that take the most time and power to run, whereas the analysis scripts that produce the results for the paper are much smaller and can be run locally. So we might save model and/or data artefacts in our repository with our code and perform CA on this last step. In the meantime, the larger simulation code runs on a schedule on HPC facilities to produce model/data artefacts.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In an ideal world, the simulation code would be written such that it has a test case which can be run to test functionality and usage. This is often a smaller simulation that sacrifices resolution in order to test functionality within a reasonable time-frame.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There are some other factors to consider when testing code on HPC systems - such as billing, user logins, scheduling and queuing - which we won’t cover here.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;conclusion&quot;&gt;Conclusion&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Building an effective continuous integration, delivery or analysis pipeline is a balancing act between getting useful information about potential changes, and allowing the developers to maintain focus and work at a good pace. Being selective and risk-focused in the design of your pipeline makes sure your team gets important information as responsively as possible.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Sarah and Graham would like to acknowledge the very helpful comments from &lt;a href=&quot;https://uk.linkedin.com/in/tim-powell-99411978&quot;&gt;Tim Powell&lt;/a&gt; concerning testing HPC code.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;This blog was originally posted by the &lt;a href=&quot;https://software.ac.uk/blog/2020-02-27-continuous-integration-fail-fast-and-fail-first&quot;&gt;Software Sustainability Institute&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Sarah Gibson</name></author><category term="continuous-integration" /><category term="tools" /><category term="devops" /><summary type="html">How to industry and academia take advantage of shared tools</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://sgibson91.github.io/images/scriberia_continuous_integration-lg.png" /><media:content medium="image" url="https://sgibson91.github.io/images/scriberia_continuous_integration-lg.png" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry><title type="html">February 2020 Update</title><link href="https://sgibson91.github.io/blog/february-2020-update/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="February 2020 Update" /><published>2020-02-23T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2020-02-23T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>https://sgibson91.github.io/blog/february-2020-update</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://sgibson91.github.io/blog/february-2020-update/">&lt;p&gt;Hello friends! :wave:
It feels like such a long time since I wrote a blog post but the truth is that I’ve just been up to so many exciting things!
So this blog post will be a quick run down on everything I’ve been up to recently.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At the start of January, I helped organise and run the &lt;a href=&quot;https://research-software-reactor.github.io/&quot;&gt;Research Software Reactor&lt;/a&gt; with &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/ixek&quot;&gt;Tania Allard&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/gerardjgorman&quot;&gt;Gerard Gorman&lt;/a&gt;.
Our topic was “&lt;a href=&quot;https://research-software-reactor.github.io/blog/devops4rse&quot;&gt;DevOps for better software and research reproducibility&lt;/a&gt;”.
We had around 30 attendees come together at the Turing Institute for 2 days and learn about &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/features/actions&quot;&gt;GitHub Actions&lt;/a&gt; for automating their workflows.
The aim was to produce reproducible software to support gold-standard research.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Later on in January, I was invited to a &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.meetup.com/PyData-Cambridge-Meetup/&quot;&gt;PyData Cambridge Meetup&lt;/a&gt; to talk about how &lt;a href=&quot;https://the-turing-way.netlify.com/introduction/introduction&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;The Turing Way&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;https://jupyter.org/binder&quot;&gt;Binder&lt;/a&gt; advocate for reproducible research.
I also ran my &lt;a href=&quot;https://bit.ly/zero-to-binder-python&quot;&gt;Zero-to-Binder tutorial&lt;/a&gt; with the attendees.
I received a lot of lovely feedback about how having an interactive session as part of the talk was really fun!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;center&gt;&lt;blockquote class=&quot;twitter-tweet&quot;&gt;&lt;p lang=&quot;en&quot; dir=&quot;ltr&quot;&gt;The first &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/PyDataCambridge?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw&quot;&gt;@PyDataCambridge&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/hashtag/meetup?src=hash&amp;amp;ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw&quot;&gt;#meetup&lt;/a&gt; in 2020: &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/drsarahlgibson?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw&quot;&gt;@drsarahlgibson&lt;/a&gt; from &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/turinginst?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw&quot;&gt;@turinginst&lt;/a&gt; on &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/hashtag/TuringWay?src=hash&amp;amp;ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw&quot;&gt;#TuringWay&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/mybinderteam?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw&quot;&gt;@mybinderteam&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://t.co/CwBYSA6QK5&quot;&gt;pic.twitter.com/CwBYSA6QK5&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&amp;mdash; PyData Cambridge (@PyDataCambridge) &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/PyDataCambridge/status/1222607971227709444?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw&quot;&gt;January 29, 2020&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt; &lt;script async=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js&quot; charset=&quot;utf-8&quot;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;&lt;/center&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I kicked off February by travelling up to Manchester to attend the &lt;a href=&quot;https://software.ac.uk/&quot;&gt;SSI&lt;/a&gt; Inaugural Fellows Meeting.
It was really wonderful to meet all the other &lt;a href=&quot;https://software.ac.uk/about/fellows&quot;&gt;Fellows&lt;/a&gt; in person, hear about our goals and figure out how to work together to achieve them.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;center&gt;&lt;blockquote class=&quot;twitter-tweet&quot;&gt;&lt;p lang=&quot;en&quot; dir=&quot;ltr&quot;&gt;So excited to meet the &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/SoftwareSaved?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw&quot;&gt;@SoftwareSaved&lt;/a&gt; 2020 Fellows today at their Inaugural Meeting! Director &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/npch?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw&quot;&gt;@npch&lt;/a&gt; kicks us off by introducing the Institute. &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/hashtag/SSIFellows2020?src=hash&amp;amp;ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw&quot;&gt;#SSIFellows2020&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://t.co/OIEIQL8dCS&quot;&gt;pic.twitter.com/OIEIQL8dCS&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&amp;mdash; Dr. Rachael Ainsworth (@rachaelevelyn) &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/rachaelevelyn/status/1227174339298107392?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw&quot;&gt;February 11, 2020&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt; &lt;script async=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js&quot; charset=&quot;utf-8&quot;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;&lt;/center&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In my free time, I visited the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.sciencemuseum.org.uk/see-and-do/top-secret&quot;&gt;Top Secret&lt;/a&gt; exhibition at the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.sciencemuseum.org.uk/&quot;&gt;Science Museum&lt;/a&gt;.
This exhibit explored ciphers and codebreaking through history, including the incredible work done by &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Alan_Turing&quot;&gt;Alan Turing&lt;/a&gt; and others at &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Bletchley_Park&quot;&gt;Bletchley Park&lt;/a&gt; during the Second World War.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;center&gt;&lt;blockquote class=&quot;twitter-tweet&quot;&gt;&lt;p lang=&quot;en&quot; dir=&quot;ltr&quot;&gt;The one encryption the code breakers at Bletchley Park couldn&amp;#39;t break was generated by the SG41. My initials! (Not my age, you cheeky lot 😉) &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/hashtag/TopSecret?src=hash&amp;amp;ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw&quot;&gt;#TopSecret&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/hashtag/Cipher?src=hash&amp;amp;ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw&quot;&gt;#Cipher&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/hashtag/Codebreaking?src=hash&amp;amp;ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw&quot;&gt;#Codebreaking&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/hashtag/AlanTuring?src=hash&amp;amp;ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw&quot;&gt;#AlanTuring&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/sciencemuseum?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw&quot;&gt;@sciencemuseum&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://t.co/g6VqS2csf6&quot;&gt;pic.twitter.com/g6VqS2csf6&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&amp;mdash; Sarah Gibson (@drsarahlgibson) &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/drsarahlgibson/status/1228681017558478848?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw&quot;&gt;February 15, 2020&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt; &lt;script async=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js&quot; charset=&quot;utf-8&quot;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;
&lt;blockquote class=&quot;twitter-tweet&quot;&gt;&lt;p lang=&quot;und&quot; dir=&quot;ltr&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://t.co/VfuBtm3xXM&quot;&gt;pic.twitter.com/VfuBtm3xXM&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&amp;mdash; Sarah Gibson (@drsarahlgibson) &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/drsarahlgibson/status/1228644026519375872?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw&quot;&gt;February 15, 2020&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt; &lt;script async=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js&quot; charset=&quot;utf-8&quot;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;&lt;/center&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And lastly, I incorporated by hobby into my open source work by creating a cross stitch kit of the Binder logo to handout to attendees of &lt;em&gt;The Turing Way&lt;/em&gt; Book Dash :books::dash:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;center&gt;&lt;blockquote class=&quot;twitter-tweet&quot;&gt;&lt;p lang=&quot;en&quot; dir=&quot;ltr&quot;&gt;And done! &lt;a href=&quot;https://t.co/M8D0ugpLwU&quot;&gt;pic.twitter.com/M8D0ugpLwU&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&amp;mdash; Sarah Gibson (@drsarahlgibson) &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/drsarahlgibson/status/1229085926363738117?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw&quot;&gt;February 16, 2020&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt; &lt;script async=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js&quot; charset=&quot;utf-8&quot;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;&lt;/center&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The attendees loved this little thank you gift for their hard work and will hopefully provide something relaxing to do after an intense day book dashing!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You’ll be able to find out more about what we got up to during the Book Dash later next week as we are supporting the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.ucu.org.uk/article/10621/UCU-announces-14-strike-days-at-74-UK-universities-in-February-and-March&quot;&gt;UCU Strike&lt;/a&gt; by respecting the digital picket line &lt;del&gt;https://medium.com/@lewisspurgin/never-cross-a-digital-picket-line-58c4249095c6&lt;/del&gt; (Update 2020-08-11: Medium account deactivated by user).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So that’s everything I’ve been up to over the last month or two.
It’s been jam-packed but incredibly fun and rewarding :sparkling_heart:
See you next month with another update!!&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Sarah Gibson</name></author><summary type="html">See what Sarah's been up to in Jan/Feb</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://sgibson91.github.io/images/february-lg.png" /><media:content medium="image" url="https://sgibson91.github.io/images/february-lg.png" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Software Sustainability Fellowship 2020</title><link href="https://sgibson91.github.io/blog/ssi-fellowship/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Software Sustainability Fellowship 2020" /><published>2020-01-10T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2020-01-10T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>https://sgibson91.github.io/blog/ssi-fellowship</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://sgibson91.github.io/blog/ssi-fellowship/">&lt;p&gt;So 2020 is off to an incredibly exciting start!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;I have been awarded a Software Sustainability Institute 2020 Fellowship!!!&lt;/strong&gt; :tada: :tada: :tada:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;center&gt;
&lt;blockquote class=&quot;twitter-tweet&quot;&gt;&lt;p lang=&quot;en&quot; dir=&quot;ltr&quot;&gt;We are thrilled to announce the new cohort of &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/SoftwareSaved?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw&quot;&gt;@SoftwareSaved&lt;/a&gt; Fellows for 2020! You can find out more about the new cohort here: &lt;a href=&quot;https://t.co/WPTePa3hoP&quot;&gt;https://t.co/WPTePa3hoP&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Congratulations to the SSI Fellows 2020! &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/hashtag/SSIFellows2020?src=hash&amp;amp;ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw&quot;&gt;#SSIFellows2020&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/hashtag/BetterSoftwareBetterResearch?src=hash&amp;amp;ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw&quot;&gt;#BetterSoftwareBetterResearch&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://t.co/zX21yvZo3h&quot;&gt;pic.twitter.com/zX21yvZo3h&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&amp;mdash; SSI - software.ac.uk (@SoftwareSaved) &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/SoftwareSaved/status/1215572740381372416?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw&quot;&gt;January 10, 2020&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt; &lt;script async=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js&quot; charset=&quot;utf-8&quot;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;
&lt;/center&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The &lt;a href=&quot;https://software.ac.uk&quot;&gt;Software Sustainability Institute&lt;/a&gt; (SSI) is an organisation that facilitates the advancement of software in research by cultivating better, more sustainable, research software to enable world-class research (“Better software, better research”).
Its mission is to become the world-leading hub for research software practice.
The Institute is based at the Universities of Edinburgh, Manchester, Oxford and Southampton, and draws on a team of experts with a breadth of experience in software development, project and programme management, research facilitation, publicity and community engagement.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Every year, the SSI runs a &lt;a href=&quot;https://software.ac.uk/programmes-and-events/fellowship-programme&quot;&gt;fellowship programme&lt;/a&gt; that provides funding for researchers who want to improve how research software is used in their domains/areas of work.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I plan to use my Fellowship to nurture the Binder community, particularly those who use Julia and R languages, and develop an on-ramp process for onboarding new &lt;a href=&quot;https://mybinder.org&quot;&gt;mybinder.org&lt;/a&gt; operators.
Hopefully, I’ll get to attend the &lt;a href=&quot;https://2020.erum.io/&quot;&gt;European R Users Meeting&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;https://juliacon.org/2020/&quot;&gt;JuliaCon&lt;/a&gt; and listen to the hopes and dreams of these sections of our community for Binder.
I also hope to work with &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/alan-turing-institute/the-turing-way&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;The Turing Way&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt; to host a “Train the Trainer”-style do-athon for educators who may want to use Binder for their courses and encourage them the contribute documentation or bug fixes back.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’m really excited and privileged to be a part of this programme and have the opportunity to collaborate with a great group of Fellows!
And stay tuned for more blog posts on what I get up to as a Fellow over the next year!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You can see my video application below.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;center&gt;
  &lt;video width=&quot;640&quot; height=&quot;360&quot; controls=&quot;&quot;&gt;
    &lt;source src=&quot;https://www.dropbox.com/s/kcf4s75zdk6hg54/sarah-gibson.mp4?raw=1&quot; type=&quot;video/mp4&quot; /&gt;
    Your browser does not support the video tag.
  &lt;/video&gt;
&lt;/center&gt;</content><author><name>Sarah Gibson</name></author><category term="announcement" /><category term="community" /><summary type="html">So 2020 is off to an incredibly exciting start!</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://sgibson91.github.io/images/ssi-lg.png" /><media:content medium="image" url="https://sgibson91.github.io/images/ssi-lg.png" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry><title type="html">2019: Seasons of Reflection</title><link href="https://sgibson91.github.io/blog/seasons-of-reflection/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="2019: Seasons of Reflection" /><published>2019-12-19T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2019-12-19T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>https://sgibson91.github.io/blog/seasons-of-reflection</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://sgibson91.github.io/blog/seasons-of-reflection/">&lt;p&gt;As 2019 comes to a close, I have spent a full year as a Research Software Engineer (RSE) at The Alan Turing Institute.
A lot has changed over the last 12 months and I’ve come a long way - sometimes surprising myself!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;winter-snowflake&quot;&gt;Winter :snowflake:&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In February, I gave my first professional talk at the &lt;a href=&quot;https://cloud.ac.uk/workshops/feb2019/&quot;&gt;UKRI Cloud Working Group workshop&lt;/a&gt; hosted by The Francis Crick Institute.
It wasn’t the furthest I’ve travelled for a conference giving it’s next door to the British Library, but it was certainly good practice!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/alan-turing-institute/the-turing-way/blob/master/conferences/presentations/UKRI_cloud_2019-02-12/UKRI_cloud_demo_2019-02-12.md&quot;&gt;gave a presentation&lt;/a&gt; on why reproducibility is important in scientific research and how Binder can be used to capture the computational environment so analyses can be reliably re-run.
It involved &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/binder-examples/matplotlib-versions&quot;&gt;live demonstrations of Binder launches&lt;/a&gt;, which was quite nerve-wracking!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;spring-tulip&quot;&gt;Spring :tulip:&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As we moved into spring, the workshops ramped up!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/alan-turing-institute/the-turing-way&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;The Turing Way&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt; ran &lt;strong&gt;three&lt;/strong&gt; workshops in March alone!
Two for researchers who’d like to use Binder and one for RSEs who may want to run a BinderHub as a service for researchers.
Preparing for the BinderHub workshop was particularly challenging as deploying one wasn’t something I’d been successful at yet!
Thankfully, a breakthrough was made with enough time to write the workshop.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Next on the list was &lt;a href=&quot;https://software.ac.uk/cw19&quot;&gt;Collaborations Workshop 2019&lt;/a&gt; hosted by the &lt;a href=&quot;https://software.ac.uk/&quot;&gt;Software Sustainability Institute&lt;/a&gt;.
This was a fascinating event for me to attend as it was the first time I interacted with open source/research/science concepts outside of Project Binder and &lt;em&gt;The Turing Way&lt;/em&gt;.
It was extra special as &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/PHerterich/status/1113090148143714304&quot;&gt;we officially launched the book part of &lt;em&gt;The Turing Way&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt; at CW19, and &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/mybinderteam/status/1141448994821955584&quot;&gt;I was invited to join the mybinder.org operating team&lt;/a&gt; as well!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In May, I attended the &lt;a href=&quot;https://research-software-reactor.github.io/blog/rsr0&quot;&gt;Microsoft Research Software Reactor Sprint&lt;/a&gt; and lead a team to develop the &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/alan-turing-institute/binderhub-deploy&quot;&gt;One-Click deployment BinderHub&lt;/a&gt;!
You can read all about it in my blog post &lt;a href=&quot;/blog/diving-into-leadership/&quot;&gt;“Diving into Leadership to Build Push-Button Code”&lt;/a&gt;.
Then the last event of spring was a &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/alan-turing-institute/the-turing-way/tree/master/workshops/book-dash&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;Turing Way&lt;/em&gt; Book Dash&lt;/a&gt; :books::dash: during which I wrote &lt;em&gt;an entire chapter&lt;/em&gt; :scream: on &lt;a href=&quot;https://the-turing-way.netlify.com/binderhub/binderhub.html&quot;&gt;BinderHub&lt;/a&gt;!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;summer-sunny&quot;&gt;Summer :sunny:&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Thankfully, summer involved a lot less travelling and presenting.
I was able to enjoy some of the good weather :sunglasses:
However, the hard work didn’t stop!
I was working away to produce the next round of workshops coming up in the autumn!
I also began working on some very exciting plans for the &lt;a href=&quot;https://blog.jupyter.org/the-international-binder-federation-4f6235c1537e&quot;&gt;Binder Federation&lt;/a&gt;!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;autumn-maple_leaf&quot;&gt;Autumn :maple_leaf:&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In autumn, I travelled again for some more workshops.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;First off was a &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/drsarahlgibson/status/1170405261070221312&quot;&gt;trip to Oslo to meet some of the Binder team&lt;/a&gt; in person!
It was a wonderful experience to be in the same room as this team as we usually collaborate remotely.
Erik and I worked together to enable HTTPS with &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;cert-manager&lt;/code&gt; on the Turing’s private BinderHub, Hub23.
Sometimes knowledge is more easily transferred from person to person, rather than through a screen.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Next was &lt;a href=&quot;https://rse.ac.uk/conf2019/&quot;&gt;RSE Con UK&lt;/a&gt; where I was super busy presenting!
I was asked to sit on the “RSE Worldwide” panel to discuss collaboration across borders and how we achieve this in the Binder team.
And I ran my &lt;a href=&quot;https://bit.ly/zero-to-binderhub-workshop&quot;&gt;Zero-to-BinderHub&lt;/a&gt; workshop again, teaching more people how to deploy BinderHubs on Azure!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After an incredibly busy year, I also managed to take some time off in autumn and go travelling around the east coast of Australia.
Though I still managed to find time to run an Open Source Dash for the Research Engineering team (this is an afternoon where we work together to contribute to open source projects)!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;table&gt;
  &lt;thead&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;th style=&quot;text-align: center&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/horse_riding.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Horse Riding in Australia&quot; /&gt;&lt;/th&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
  &lt;/thead&gt;
  &lt;tbody&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td style=&quot;text-align: center&quot;&gt;I went horseback riding along Cape Tribulation beach in the Daintree Rainforest area of northern Queensland! The horse’s name is Basil :sparkling_heart:&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
  &lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Overall, I’m really proud of how my presenting skills and confidence in public speaking have improved over 2019.
Giving workshops and lectures/teaching was never something I imagined I would enjoy or be terribly good at - and yet, I’ve completely surprised myself at how wrong I was!
Though absolutely no-one who helped me achieve all of this will be the slightest bit surprised :wink::heart:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’m very grateful for all the opportunities I’ve been given this year to learn, grow and share my new knowledge and experiences.
I can’t wait to see what’s coming next!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So I’m coming into 2020 like…&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;table&gt;
  &lt;thead&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;th style=&quot;text-align: center&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://metro.co.uk/wp-content/uploads/2019/10/kick-new-56b2.gif&quot; /&gt;&lt;/th&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
  &lt;/thead&gt;
  &lt;tbody&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td style=&quot;text-align: center&quot;&gt;Johannes Radebe, &lt;em&gt;Strictly Come Dancing&lt;/em&gt;, BBC 2019&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td style=&quot;text-align: center&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=tYSFo-YBaQM&quot;&gt;Watch the full routine on YouTube&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
  &lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;</content><author><name>Sarah Gibson</name></author><category term="reflection" /><category term="growth" /><summary type="html">Sarah reflects on her accomplishments in 2019</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://sgibson91.github.io/images/seasonal-reflections-lg.png" /><media:content medium="image" url="https://sgibson91.github.io/images/seasonal-reflections-lg.png" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry><title type="html">The Turing Way</title><link href="https://sgibson91.github.io/projects/the-turing-way/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="The Turing Way" /><published>2019-11-27T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2019-11-27T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>https://sgibson91.github.io/projects/the-turing-way</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://sgibson91.github.io/projects/the-turing-way/">&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;The Turing Way&lt;/em&gt; is an online handbook - and global community - dedicated to fostering gold-standard reproducible research.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;It’s a cultural movement with the potential to transform data science.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There is a crisis of reproducibility in science. ‘Publish-or-perish’ incentives and excessive data secrecy stifles progress and wastes resources: siloed science is slow science.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;The Turing Way&lt;/em&gt; is an evolving online ‘handbook’ on how to conduct world-leading, reproducible research in academic data science and AI with the goal of making reproducible science “too easy not to do”. The book deals not only with the ‘how’ of things, but also the ‘why’ - the ethos and long-term benefits of reproducible research.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;The Turing Way&lt;/em&gt; is also a flourishing global community of research engineers, data librarians, industry professionals and research experts dedicated to capturing and sharing research best practice, tools and data. The team is collaborating on workshops with the people behind &lt;a href=&quot;https://binderhub.readthedocs.io/en/latest/&quot;&gt;Binder&lt;/a&gt;, a key research platform that enables highly shareable research.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Through the community contributions, the handbook will grow into a ‘How-To Guide for Data Science’ covering areas including research design, collaboration, visualising results, the ethics of data science, and more.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Sarah was a core member of the team that launched &lt;em&gt;The Turing Way&lt;/em&gt; and specifically worked on the integration of the book with Binder. She developed and presented two workshops on using Binder (&lt;a href=&quot;https://bit.ly/zero-to-binder-python&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;Zero-to-Binder&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;) and deploying a &lt;a href=&quot;https://binderhub.readthedocs.io/en/latest/&quot;&gt;BinderHub&lt;/a&gt;, the technology that powers Binder (&lt;a href=&quot;https://bit.ly/zero-to-binderhub-workshop&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;Zero-to-BinderHub&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Sarah also contributed new documentation on deploying BinderHubs to Microsoft Azure to the Binder Project. As a result, she was asked to officially join the Binder team as an operator and maintainer of the project and &lt;a href=&quot;https://mybinder.org&quot;&gt;mybinder.org&lt;/a&gt; website.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Further reading:&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.turing.ac.uk/research/impact-stories/changing-culture-data-science&quot;&gt;Turing Impact Story: Changing the culture of data science&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Sarah Gibson</name></author><category term="reproducibility" /><category term="data-science" /><category term="community" /><summary type="html">A Handbook for Data Science</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://sgibson91.github.io/images/the-turing-way-lg.png" /><media:content medium="image" url="https://sgibson91.github.io/images/the-turing-way-lg.png" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry><title type="html">HelmUpgradeBot</title><link href="https://sgibson91.github.io/projects/helm-upgrade-bot/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="HelmUpgradeBot" /><published>2019-11-26T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2019-11-26T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>https://sgibson91.github.io/projects/helm-upgrade-bot</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://sgibson91.github.io/projects/helm-upgrade-bot/">&lt;p&gt;While managing &lt;a href=&quot;https://binderhub.readthedocs.io/en/latest/&quot;&gt;BinderHubs&lt;/a&gt;, I found that there were a lot of things I had to deal with manually and, inevitably, I failed to keep on top of them.
Most notably, the two biggest problems I faced were &lt;em&gt;i)&lt;/em&gt; keeping my BinderHub up-to-date with the latest software released by the Binder team, and &lt;em&gt;ii)&lt;/em&gt; keeping the size of the image registry manageable and within budget.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Hence I developed &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/HelmUpgradeBot&quot;&gt;HelmUpgradeBot&lt;/a&gt;!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;keeping-software-up-to-date&quot;&gt;Keeping software up-to-date&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The first problem I wanted to solve was the manual updates I had to perform to keep my BinderHub up-to-date with the software the Binder team releases, packaged as a &lt;a href=&quot;https://jupyterhub.github.io/helm-chart/&quot;&gt;Helm Chart&lt;/a&gt;.
Thankfully, this was a problem that had already been solved for &lt;a href=&quot;https://mybinder.org&quot;&gt;mybinder.org&lt;/a&gt;!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/henchc&quot;&gt;Chris Hench&lt;/a&gt; had already written &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/henchbot/mybinder.org-upgrades&quot;&gt;henchbot&lt;/a&gt; to deploy updates to mybinder.org, &lt;em&gt;and&lt;/em&gt; had written &lt;a href=&quot;https://blog.jupyter.org/automating-mybinder-org-dependency-upgrades-in-10-steps-bb5e38542059&quot;&gt;a blog post&lt;/a&gt; describing the process of creating it.
All I needed to do was tweak the code for my specific set-up - specifically, interacting with Azure resources.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/HelmUpgradeBot/hub23-deploy-upgrades/&quot;&gt;Check out the code for Helm Chart upgrades.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;interacting-with-azure&quot;&gt;Interacting with Azure&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The trick with the Helm Chart upgrades was running the bot from a place that could interact with the Azure resources I had set up to support my BinderHub - namely, the &lt;a href=&quot;https://azure.microsoft.com/en-gb/services/key-vault/&quot;&gt;Key Vault&lt;/a&gt;, which was where I chose to store my Personal Access Token rather than parse it as an environment variable (as in the henchbot example).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I needed to run this from a server that could scrape the Helm Chart page at regular intervals.
The solution that made most sense was to create a Virtual Machine in Azure and assign it a &lt;a href=&quot;https://docs.microsoft.com/en-us/azure/active-directory/managed-identities-azure-resources/overview#how-a-system-assigned-managed-identity-works-with-an-azure-vm&quot;&gt;Managed System Identity&lt;/a&gt; with enough permissions to read from the Key Vault.
The bot could then login to Azure using the identity of the VM it was running on, and retrieve the PAT from the Key Vault.
Once I had perfected this section of the code, it was just a matter of following Chris’s blog post to code the interactions with GitHub (for example, create a fork and pull request) and then deploy the code as a &lt;a href=&quot;https://crontab.guru/&quot;&gt;cron job&lt;/a&gt; on the Azure VM to perform a daily check for updates.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;cleaning-up-artifacts&quot;&gt;Cleaning up artifacts&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One thing that BinderHubs produce is a &lt;em&gt;lot&lt;/em&gt; of Docker images.
If you’re using a private Docker registry, such as &lt;a href=&quot;https://azure.microsoft.com/en-gb/services/container-registry/&quot;&gt;Azure Container Registry&lt;/a&gt;, then the size (and hence the cost!) can soar very quickly.
So I wanted to apply what I’d learned deploying the Helm Chart upgrades to automatically clean out my Docker registry at regular intervals.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/HelmUpgradeBot/DockerCleanUp/&quot;&gt;Check out the code for cleaning a Docker registry.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I already had a basis for how to deploy such a code:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;:heavy_check_mark: Programmatically interacting with Azure login&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;:heavy_check_mark: Virtual Machines with access to cloud resources&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;:heavy_check_mark: Writing cron expressions&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Next, I began to investigate how to &lt;a href=&quot;https://docs.microsoft.com/en-us/cli/azure/acr?view=azure-cli-latest&quot;&gt;programmatically interact with the Docker registry&lt;/a&gt; itself.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I wanted to sort the images both by age and size since large images will obviously fill the repository up more quickly, and older images are less likely to be actively used or have been rebuilt under a different tag.
I achieved this by scraping the manifests of the repositories and images within the registry and creating a dataframe to sort the images.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I also created an “aggressive” mode which would activate when the total size of the registry exceeds a pre-set, tuneable limit.
This would then delete the largest images in order to bring the size under the prescribed limit.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Currently, this bot runs monthly to check the size of the registry isn’t growing too large.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Sarah Gibson</name></author><category term="reproducibility" /><category term="binderhub" /><category term="automation" /><summary type="html">A Bot to manage BinderHubs</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://sgibson91.github.io/images/helmupgradebot-lg.png" /><media:content medium="image" url="https://sgibson91.github.io/images/helmupgradebot-lg.png" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Binder</title><link href="https://sgibson91.github.io/projects/binder/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Binder" /><published>2019-11-25T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2019-11-25T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>https://sgibson91.github.io/projects/binder</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://sgibson91.github.io/projects/binder/">&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://mybinder.readthedocs.io/en/latest/&quot;&gt;Binder&lt;/a&gt; is a project that allows users to create custom computing environments that can be shared and used by many remote users. It is powered by &lt;a href=&quot;https://binderhub.readthedocs.io/en/latest/&quot;&gt;BinderHub&lt;/a&gt;, which is an open-source tool that deploys the Binder service in the cloud.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One such Binder service is &lt;a href=&quot;https://mybinder.org&quot;&gt;mybinder.org&lt;/a&gt; and is free to use. More information about mybinder.org and the team that runs is can be found on the &lt;a href=&quot;https://mybinder.readthedocs.io/en/latest/about.html#about&quot;&gt;“About mybinder.org”&lt;/a&gt; page.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As a member of the Binder operating team, Sarah’s role involves maintaining the mybinder.org website, responding to issues and/or contributions on &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/jupyterhub/binderhub&quot;&gt;GitHub&lt;/a&gt; and in the &lt;a href=&quot;https://gitter.im/jupyterhub/binder&quot;&gt;gitter channel&lt;/a&gt;, and providing documentation.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Sarah is also the Microsoft Azure expert when it comes to deploying BinderHubs and has written a &lt;a href=&quot;https://bit.ly/zero-to-binderhub-workshop&quot;&gt;step-by-step workshop&lt;/a&gt; that teaches others to do this. She has deployed and maintains a private BinderHub instance at &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.turing.ac.uk/&quot;&gt;The Alan Turing Institute&lt;/a&gt;, known as &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/alan-turing-institute/hub23-deploy&quot;&gt;Hub23&lt;/a&gt;, hosted on Azure.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Sarah Gibson</name></author><category term="reproducibility" /><category term="cloud" /><category term="community" /><category term="open-source" /><summary type="html">Turn a git repo into a collection of interactive notebooks</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://sgibson91.github.io/images/binder-lg.png" /><media:content medium="image" url="https://sgibson91.github.io/images/binder-lg.png" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Diving into Leadership to Build Push-Button Code</title><link href="https://sgibson91.github.io/blog/diving-into-leadership/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Diving into Leadership to Build Push-Button Code" /><published>2019-10-17T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2019-10-17T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>https://sgibson91.github.io/blog/diving-into-leadership</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://sgibson91.github.io/blog/diving-into-leadership/">&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;“Hi everyone, I’m Sarah! I’m a Research Data Scientist at the Alan Turing Institute and I’m also an operator of mybinder.org. It’s really cool seeing how many people here are interested in BinderHub!”&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And it is cool. &lt;em&gt;Really&lt;/em&gt; cool! But also a bit scary as a room full of Research Software Engineers (each of them much further on in their careers than I am) suddenly turn to me, eager for the knowledge I was surely about to impart to them.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But let’s rewind a bit.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;joining-the-binder-community&quot;&gt;Joining the Binder community&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It’s May 2019 and I’m attending the Research Software Reactor sprint jointly hosted by Microsoft and Imperial College London. This is a 3-day hackathon where researchers from different areas (though all with a computing background) come together to collaboratively build cloud-based resources on Microsoft’s Azure platform.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As for me, I’m only 6 months into my role at the Turing, having graduated from my PhD in Astrophysics at the start of the year. Also, my role as a “Binder Operator” is barely 2 months old… which is why I’m starting to feel nervous about the amount of interest in the room! This also happens to be the second hackathon I’ve attended &lt;em&gt;ever&lt;/em&gt;, so the adrenaline is high.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So, what is this “Binder” that we’re all so excited about?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://mybinder.readthedocs.io/en/latest/&quot;&gt;Binder&lt;/a&gt; is an amazing resource that can host reproducible and interactive code in a web browser. Great… what does that mean? It means that if I have some scripts or notebooks in a repository (like &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/binder-examples/requirements&quot;&gt;this one&lt;/a&gt;) and I describe the packages in a configuration file (such as &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/binder-examples/requirements/blob/master/requirements.txt&quot;&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;requirements.txt&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/a&gt;), then I can go to &lt;a href=&quot;https://mybinder.org&quot;&gt;mybinder.org&lt;/a&gt;, copy the URL of the repository into the form and hit launch. This will begin a series of events culminating in my notebook appearing in a browser window with all of the packages installed, and the code will &lt;em&gt;just run&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Sounds like magic, right? You can even combine Binder with &lt;a href=&quot;https://jupyterbook.org&quot;&gt;Jupyter Books&lt;/a&gt; to create &lt;a href=&quot;https://joergbrech.github.io/Modellbildung-und-Simulation/intro&quot;&gt;interactive documents&lt;/a&gt;! Below is a comic explaining how a scientist may use Binder.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;table&gt;
  &lt;thead&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;th style=&quot;text-align: center&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://pbs.twimg.com/media/DwYDGULWkAASgjS.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Binder comic&quot; /&gt;&lt;/th&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
  &lt;/thead&gt;
  &lt;tbody&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td style=&quot;text-align: center&quot;&gt;The user experience of mybinder.org. Comic courtesy of &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/mybinderteam/status/1082556317842264064&quot;&gt;Juliette Taka&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
  &lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://binderhub.readthedocs.io/en/latest/index.html&quot;&gt;BinderHub&lt;/a&gt; is the technology powering Binder (or where the magic happens). It is a multi-user server that can create a custom, user-specified computing environment and make it accessible via a URL. It utilises different tools to make this possible and can be deployed onto either a cloud provider or an on-premise compute cluster. These tools are depicted in the below illustration.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;table&gt;
  &lt;thead&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;th style=&quot;text-align: center&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://zenodo.org/api/iiif/v2/e4125eaf-b456-4097-85fc-6a2e80482d1c:96c70193-2f9e-442d-8cf8-21485d8864e1:1728_TURI_Book%20sprint_45%20repo2docker_040619_v2_MK.jpg/full/750,/0/default.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;BinderHub tools&quot; /&gt;&lt;/th&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
  &lt;/thead&gt;
  &lt;tbody&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td style=&quot;text-align: center&quot;&gt;A pictorial representation of the different tools constituting BinderHub. This image was created by &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.scriberia.co.uk/&quot;&gt;Scriberia&lt;/a&gt; for &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/alan-turing-institute/the-turing-way&quot;&gt;The Turing Way&lt;/a&gt; community and is used under a CC-BY licence. &lt;a href=&quot;https://doi.org/10.5281/zenodo.3332808&quot;&gt;Zenodo record&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
  &lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Since BinderHub is a cloud-neutral technology (mybinder.org itself runs on &lt;a href=&quot;https://blog.jupyter.org/the-international-binder-federation-4f6235c1537e&quot;&gt;Google Cloud and OVH.com&lt;/a&gt;), I previously worked on refining the documentation around deploying BinderHub on Azure and ran workshops teaching people how to use Binder and deploy BinderHub. It was this work that lead to me being invited to join the Binder team. Being a maintainer for an open-source project involves checking if the service is still running smoothly and being an active, friendly member of the community - one who can answer questions when they arise.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now that we’ve covered a bit of background, let’s get back to my slightly uncomfortable moment at the sprint.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;day-1-an-unexpected-leadership-position&quot;&gt;Day 1: An unexpected leadership position&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Everybody in the room is now trying to whittle down which projects we should work on - all of which are awesome! The magic of BinderHub is that it covers so many aspects of software engineering tools and practices, such as continuous integration/deployment and &lt;a href=&quot;https://kubernetes.io/&quot;&gt;Kubernetes&lt;/a&gt;. The BinderHub idea is quickly amassing a lot of satellite projects!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;“So Sarah, is it OK if I name you leader of ‘Team BinderHub’?”&lt;/em&gt; My second uncomfortable moment. Gerard Gorman, Senior Lecturer in the Department of Earth Sciences at Imperial and co-organiser of the sprint, has just elected me leader of my first ever hack project. If I’m honest, I’d intended to spend the sprint ironing out some niggles with a colleague. But I’ve always been a “learn by doing” person so I agree and desperately begin wracking my brain for a project to give my team for the next 3 days.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After a bit of shuffling (where for a while it seemed like most of the attendees would be joining ‘Team BinderHub’!), I finally assemble a team. My teammates are: Tania Allard, a Microsoft Developer Advocate; Tim Greaves and Diego Alonso Álvarez, Research Software Engineers at Imperial; and Gerard himself.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The project I decide to bring to the table is one that I’d started but had stalled. The process of deploying a BinderHub can be quite long (usually an hour) and consists mainly of typing stuff into the command line. So a couple of months prior, I’d begun designing a set of scripts that would install the relevant tools, deploy a BinderHub on Azure and connect it to a Docker Hub account, retrieve various pieces of information (IP addresses, logs, etc.) and then remove the BinderHub from the cloud. However, my bash scripting and operating system knowledge is not especially strong. Within the team, we have a bit of a discussion around the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.microsoft.com/developerblog/2017/01/17/the-deploy-to-azure-button/&quot;&gt;Deploy to Azure&lt;/a&gt; feature - a button that can be copy-pasted into the README of a GitHub project and facilitates a one-click deployment of the project to Azure. It seems like the perfect hack is to combine my scripts with the deploy button and make deploying BinderHub as easy as possible.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tim is a bash scripting, containerising pro and has a little experience with the Azure “blue button” from the &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/okpy/ok&quot;&gt;OKPy&lt;/a&gt; project. I ask him to check my setup script that installs the required Command Line Interfaces (CLIs) and explain that I’d like it to be generalised for different operating systems.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Gerard is a BinderHub enthusiast and is keen to get one deployed as a teaching resource at Imperial. As a starter task, I ask him to read up on how the blue button works.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Diego has never heard of Binder or BinderHub before and is quite confused as to what the rest of the team are so excited about! I suggest that he works through my &lt;a href=&quot;https://bit.ly/zero-to-binderhub-workshop&quot;&gt;Zero to BinderHub workshop&lt;/a&gt; in order to bring him up to speed with the concepts. This is also the perfect opportunity to get feedback on my workshop if parts are not clear! I encourage him to open an issue describing any problems he comes across or extra information he’d like to see.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And just like that, I find I’ve delegated myself out of a job!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now Impostor Syndrome is beginning to creep up on me. Not only is it taking four extra people to pull together my work and make it usable, but I am also unsure how I would assist them in these tasks I’d set them. Especially Tim as the complexity of what I wanted the bash scripts to achieve was what had caused the project to stall in the first place.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Except there’s one very important aspect of any software project I’ve not mentioned yet: Documentation!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Since starting my position at the Turing, I’ve come to fully appreciate how fundamental good documentation is to the success of a project. Clearly written instructions covering the purpose of the project, how to install/run the code, and what kind of inputs/outputs to expect make it much easier for a new person to quickly get to grips with the project. And as result, it’s far more likely to be referenced and reused. While my team begin familiarising themselves with the infrastructure and goals of my project, I begin an overhaul of the documentation whilst keeping an eye on the repo to manage incoming issues and pull requests.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Take that, Impostor Syndrome!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;day-2-the-team-makes-progress&quot;&gt;Day 2: The team makes progress&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It’s the second day of the sprint and ‘Team BinderHub’ gather again, our enthusiasm not diminished yet!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I very quickly set goals for the day. I want the button to work by the end of the day as I’m hoping the final day can be used to work on an idea Tania has to use &lt;a href=&quot;https://azure.microsoft.com/en-gb/services/devops/pipelines/&quot;&gt;Azure’s DevOps Pipelines&lt;/a&gt; to automatically update the deployed BinderHub as new commits come into the host repo. This would be a very handy feature for those (like me!) maintaining BinderHubs at their own institutions. Anything to automate and reduce the number of commands we have to type!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I ask Tim to begin working on the deploy script itself, to add tests where necessary and tidy up some of the parsing of the variables. The next steps are to build a Dockerfile that runs the deploy script and an &lt;a href=&quot;https://docs.microsoft.com/en-gb/azure/azure-resource-manager/resource-group-overview&quot;&gt;ARM (Azure Resource Manager) template&lt;/a&gt; that controls the form the blue button links to.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Again, I’m managing the documentation, keeping up with changes we make to the code-base and functionality. Similarly, I keep watch over the repo to manage incoming pull requests and merge conflicts and also make a start on the amendments to the BinderHub workshop Diego has compiled.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My Impostor Syndrome is definitely subsiding as I begin to feel more like I understand the skills of my team and we are all making the best use of our time.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;day-3-document-document-document&quot;&gt;Day 3: Document, document, document&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For the third and final day of the sprint we are in a new venue: the Microsoft Reactor. This is a workspace in the Shoreditch area of London where we are offered free pizza and cookies and a DJ to provide the soundtrack to our code. (OK, less an &lt;em&gt;actual&lt;/em&gt; DJ, more of a software engineer with Spotify Premium. :stuck_out_tongue_winking_eye:) What I will say though, Microsoft’s beverage-making facilities have nothing on the Turing’s iPad coffee maker! :wink:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Our goals for the last day? Consolidate and document! Ideally get the button working if possible, but the top priority is to make it as easy as possible for the team (or someone new!) to come along to the repo and finish what we have started.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We decide that there isn’t enough time left or infrastructure in place to implement the Azure DevOps Pipeline for automatic upgrades; instead, Tania begins working on a tutorial so we can implement it later.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tim and I end up in a bit of GitHub hell as we realise that the code to create the Kubernetes cluster is in the setup script, not the deploy script. We refactor some parts so that all of the resources are deployed from the deploy script, and this also means that the Dockerfile only needs to find one script to execute. However, this refactoring causes a complicated merge conflict and some of the bug fixes Tim implemented disappear in a squash merge. (This sounded difficult enough to resolve that I’ve been put off learning about squash merges since!) As team leader, I try to orchestrate whose pull request should be merged first so that all the right code ends up in master.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;what-did-we-learn-and-do&quot;&gt;What did we learn and do?&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;By the end of the sprint, we don’t quite have a working button deployment, but we do have:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;a set of streamlined scripts for auto-deployment based on the contents of a JSON file,&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;an ARM template and Dockerfile that will provide the back-end to the blue button after some further debugging,&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;a plan to move the project forwards after the sprint.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So what did I learn from those three days?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;coding-with-other-people-is-fun&quot;&gt;Coding with other people is fun!&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Pair programming is something we try to achieve at the Turing, but it can be difficult to do depending on the project and the time constraints of those working on it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This was the first time I’d experienced true collaboration. Where I had an idea that I wasn’t sure how to implement, and someone with the skills had helped me shape it and realise it. It gave me a sense of community and belonging. I hope I’ve forged connections with ‘Team BinderHub’ that will last the duration of our careers and we can work together again.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;theres-a-role-for-everyone-in-a-team-and-these-are-equally-important&quot;&gt;There’s a role for everyone in a team and these are equally important&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Even if it’s reviewing code or writing documentation, these are as important (arguably, more so) than the code itself. Code that does what you think it’s doing and has been explained well will have a much longer lifespan than code that is difficult to follow, regardless of how clever it is, and poorly documented.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;i-found-my-strength-as-a-leader&quot;&gt;I found my strength as a leader&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You might remember at the beginning of this blog post I mentioned that I’d never led a hack project before, so I also learned a lot about my leadership capabilities.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I think I did well. I identified the strengths of each of my team members and gave them a task suited to them whilst letting them explore new concepts, offering my own insight and opinions when required.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I also think that it was a good choice for me to not be too involved in the coding aspect of this project. Managing the flow into the repo and updating the documentation as new code came in meant that I managed to maintain an overall perspective of the project and could switch gears as questions came in from different areas. I don’t think I could have maintained such a view if I’d been buried in code and I can always learn from the scripts we’ve developed at a later point.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;hackathons-are-not-where-projects-end&quot;&gt;Hackathons are not where projects end&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;While the first 80% of a project to get the infrastructure in place can be achieved in a short amount of time like a hackathon, the last 20% is &lt;strong&gt;hard&lt;/strong&gt; and often takes longer. But this extra effort is necessary for the software to be taken up by others.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;‘Team BinderHub’ continued working on this project over Slack and GitHub to finally make our &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/alan-turing-institute/binderhub-deploy/releases&quot;&gt;version 1 release&lt;/a&gt; on &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/ixek/status/1138422778040922112&quot;&gt;June 11th&lt;/a&gt; - almost 3 weeks after the end of the sprint!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you’d like to try the button to deploy your own BinderHub (or contribute a new feature!), the repo can be found here :point_right: &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/alan-turing-institute/binderhub-deploy&quot;&gt;alan-turing-institute/binderhub-deploy&lt;/a&gt;. Look for the button below!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://azuredeploy.net/deploybutton.svg&quot; alt=&quot;Deploy to Azure button&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;thank-you-sparkling_heart&quot;&gt;Thank You! :sparkling_heart:&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’d like to thank a few people who made this possible:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Gerard, Imperial College, Tania and Lee Stott from Microsoft for organising such an inspiring event;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;‘Team BinderHub’ for coming along on this wild ride with me;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;The Binder Team for accepting me into the community and giving me the space to develop such projects;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;and &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/alan-turing-institute/the-turing-way&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;The Turing Way&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt; team who introduced me to Binder and the value of community (and documentation!).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Note: this is cross-posted with &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.turing.ac.uk/research/research-programmes/research-engineering/programme-articles/diving-leadership-build-push-button-code&quot;&gt;The Alan Turing Institute blog&lt;/a&gt; and the &lt;a href=&quot;https://blog.jupyter.org/diving-into-leadership-to-build-push-button-code-df2a075c9914&quot;&gt;Jupyter blog&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Sarah Gibson</name></author><category term="hackathon" /><category term="sprint" /><category term="binder" /><category term="binderhub" /><category term="leadership" /><category term="microsoft" /><category term="azure" /><category term="cloud" /><summary type="html">Sarah's experiences at the Microsoft Reactor Sprint 2019</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://sgibson91.github.io/images/diving-into-leadership-lg.png" /><media:content medium="image" url="https://sgibson91.github.io/images/diving-into-leadership-lg.png" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry></feed>