<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Home on</title><link>https://sgibson91.github.io/</link><description>Recent content in Home on</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-gb</language><lastBuildDate>Sun, 07 Mar 2021 19:50:11 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://sgibson91.github.io/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Collaborations Workshop 2021</title><link>https://sgibson91.github.io/blog/collabw21/</link><pubDate>Thu, 15 Apr 2021 19:13:50 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://sgibson91.github.io/blog/collabw21/</guid><description>At the end of March 2021, I attended the Collaborations Workshop hosted by the Software Sustainability Institute. The following is my roundup of what the event is, who runs it, and some of my highlights.
What is the SSI? The Software Sustainability Institute (SSI for short) is a network of UK universities, Research Software Engineering groups and policy makers dedicated in improving the quality, sustainability and recognition of research software. They help the members in their network learn software skills and best practices, and advocate for culture change in their organisations and institutions.</description></item><item><title>Media</title><link>https://sgibson91.github.io/media/</link><pubDate>Sun, 07 Mar 2021 19:45:11 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://sgibson91.github.io/media/</guid><description>A collection of external media posts that discuss projects that Sarah is involved in or that have interviewed Sarah directly (in reverse chronological order).
The Turing Podcast, Episode #15 - Reproducible Data Science: How hard can it be? CogX 2020 Tools, Practices, and Systems panel Software Sustainability Institute Fellowship 2020 announcement and profile &amp;ldquo;Make code accessible with these cloud services&amp;rdquo; Nature 575, 247-248 (2019) Interview with Ines Juvan-Beaulieu for the Exploring New Worlds blog Impact Story about The Turing Way project by The Alan Turing Institute &amp;ldquo;BinderHub is out of beta!</description></item><item><title>Speaking</title><link>https://sgibson91.github.io/speaking/</link><pubDate>Sun, 07 Mar 2021 19:42:32 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://sgibson91.github.io/speaking/</guid><description>I have spoken on reproducible research and open source collaboration at high profile software conferences in the UK. I am also comfortable and experienced at leading workshops/tutorials for all ranges of abilities.
I am always happy to attend and speak at conferences, and I really enjoy sharing my knowledge with new audiences. I am grateful to all the conference organisers who have done a wonderful job hosting me so far. 👐</description></item><item><title>Continuous Integration: Fail Fast and Fail First</title><link>https://sgibson91.github.io/blog/continuous-integration/</link><pubDate>Thu, 27 Feb 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://sgibson91.github.io/blog/continuous-integration/</guid><description>Sarah and Graham have different career backgrounds - Sarah having come through academia whereas Graham earned his stripes in industry. However in their current roles, they often find themselves using the same tools, for example Continuous Integration. They have written this blog post to identify how academia and industry may use Continuous Integration in different ways, and what they might learn from one another.
What is Continuous Integration and why do we use it?</description></item><item><title>February 2020 Update</title><link>https://sgibson91.github.io/blog/february-2020-update/</link><pubDate>Sun, 23 Feb 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://sgibson91.github.io/blog/february-2020-update/</guid><description>Hello friends! 👋 It feels like such a long time since I wrote a blog post but the truth is that I&amp;rsquo;ve just been up to so many exciting things! So this blog post will be a quick run down on everything I&amp;rsquo;ve been up to recently.
At the start of January, I helped organise and run the Research Software Reactor with Tania Allard and Gerard Gorman. Our topic was &amp;ldquo;DevOps for better software and research reproducibility&amp;rdquo;.</description></item><item><title>Software Sustainability Institute Fellowship 2020</title><link>https://sgibson91.github.io/blog/ssi-fellowship/</link><pubDate>Fri, 10 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://sgibson91.github.io/blog/ssi-fellowship/</guid><description>So 2020 is off to an incredibly exciting start!
I have been awarded a Software Sustainability Institute 2020 Fellowship!!! 🎉 🎉 🎉
We are thrilled to announce the new cohort of @SoftwareSaved Fellows for 2020! You can find out more about the new cohort here: https://t.co/WPTePa3hoP
Congratulations to the SSI Fellows 2020! #SSIFellows2020 #BetterSoftwareBetterResearch pic.twitter.com/zX21yvZo3h
&amp;mdash; The Software Sustainability Institute (@SoftwareSaved) January 10, 2020 The Software Sustainability Institute (SSI) is an organisation that facilitates the advancement of software in research by cultivating better, more sustainable, research software to enable world-class research (“Better software, better research”).</description></item><item><title>2019: Seasons of Reflection</title><link>https://sgibson91.github.io/blog/seasons-of-reflection/</link><pubDate>Thu, 19 Dec 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://sgibson91.github.io/blog/seasons-of-reflection/</guid><description>As 2019 comes to a close, I have spent a full year as a Research Software Engineer (RSE) at The Alan Turing Institute. A lot has changed over the last 12 months and I&amp;rsquo;ve come a long way - sometimes surprising myself!
Winter ❄️ In February, I gave my first professional talk at the UKRI Cloud Working Group workshop hosted by The Francis Crick Institute. It wasn&amp;rsquo;t the furthest I&amp;rsquo;ve travelled for a conference giving it&amp;rsquo;s next door to the British Library, but it was certainly good practice!</description></item><item><title>Diving Into Leadership to Build Push-Button Code</title><link>https://sgibson91.github.io/blog/diving-into-leadership/</link><pubDate>Thu, 17 Oct 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://sgibson91.github.io/blog/diving-into-leadership/</guid><description>&amp;ldquo;Hi everyone, I&amp;rsquo;m Sarah! I&amp;rsquo;m a Research Data Scientist at the Alan Turing Institute and I&amp;rsquo;m also an operator of mybinder.org. It&amp;rsquo;s really cool seeing how many people here are interested in BinderHub!&amp;quot;
And it is cool. Really cool! But also a bit scary as a room full of Research Software Engineers (each of them much further on in their careers than I am) suddenly turn to me, eager for the knowledge I was surely about to impart to them.</description></item><item><title>HelmUpgradeBot</title><link>https://sgibson91.github.io/project/helmupgradebot/</link><pubDate>Fri, 05 Jul 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://sgibson91.github.io/project/helmupgradebot/</guid><description>While managing BinderHubs, I found that there were a lot of things I had to deal with manually and, inevitably, I failed to keep on top of them. Most notably, the two biggest problems I faced were i) keeping my BinderHub up-to-date with the latest software released by the Binder team, and ii) keeping the size of the image registry manageable and within budget.
Hence I developed HelmUpgradeBot!
Keeping software up-to-date The first problem I wanted to solve was the manual updates I had to perform to keep my BinderHub up-to-date with the software the Binder team releases, packaged as a Helm Chart.</description></item><item><title>Binder</title><link>https://sgibson91.github.io/project/binder/</link><pubDate>Sun, 31 Mar 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://sgibson91.github.io/project/binder/</guid><description>Binder is a project that allows users to create custom computing environments that can be shared and used by many remote users. It is powered by BinderHub, which is an open-source tool that deploys the Binder service in the cloud.
One such Binder service is mybinder.org and is free to use. More information about mybinder.org and the team that runs is can be found on the &amp;ldquo;About mybinder.org&amp;rdquo; page.
As a member of the Binder operating team, Sarah&amp;rsquo;s role involves maintaining the mybinder.</description></item><item><title>The Turing Way</title><link>https://sgibson91.github.io/project/turing-way/</link><pubDate>Mon, 31 Dec 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://sgibson91.github.io/project/turing-way/</guid><description>The Turing Way is an online handbook - and global community - dedicated to fostering gold-standard reproducible research.
It&amp;rsquo;s a cultural movement with the potential to transform data science.
There is a crisis of reproducibility in science. &amp;lsquo;Publish-or-perish&amp;rsquo; incentives and excessive data secrecy stifles progress and wastes resources: siloed science is slow science.
The Turing Way is an evolving online &amp;lsquo;handbook&amp;rsquo; on how to conduct world-leading, reproducible research in academic data science and AI with the goal of making reproducible science &amp;ldquo;too easy not to do&amp;rdquo;.</description></item></channel></rss>