<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Continuous-Deployment on</title><link>https://sgibson91.github.io/tags/continuous-deployment/</link><description>Recent content in Continuous-Deployment on</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-gb</language><lastBuildDate>Thu, 12 May 2022 11:51:52 +0100</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://sgibson91.github.io/tags/continuous-deployment/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Tech update: Multiple JupyterHubs, multiple clusters, one repository.</title><link>https://sgibson91.github.io/blog/2i2c-ci-cd-improvements/</link><pubDate>Thu, 12 May 2022 11:51:52 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://sgibson91.github.io/blog/2i2c-ci-cd-improvements/</guid><description>&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>This blog was &lt;a href="https://2i2c.org/blog/2022/ci-cd-improvements/">originally posted by 2i2c&lt;/a> and represents a project Sarah lead and developed.&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;p>2i2c manages the configuration and deployment of multiple Kubernetes clusters and JupyterHubs from &lt;a href="https://github.com/2i2c-org/infrastructure">a single open infrastructure repository&lt;/a>.
This is a challenging problem, as it requires us to centralize information about a number of &lt;em>independent&lt;/em> cloud services, and deploy them in an efficient and reliable manner.
Our initial attempt at this had a number of inefficiencies, and we recently completed an overhaul of its configuration and deployment infrastructure.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>How I automated authorised cloud deployments from Pull Requests with GitHub Actions</title><link>https://sgibson91.github.io/blog/test-this-pr/</link><pubDate>Mon, 22 Nov 2021 19:35:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://sgibson91.github.io/blog/test-this-pr/</guid><description>&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>This blog was originally posted on the Jupyter blog: &lt;a href="https://blog.jupyter.org/how-i-automated-authorised-cloud-deployments-from-pull-requests-with-github-actions-13f890538e32">https://blog.jupyter.org/how-i-automated-authorised-cloud-deployments-from-pull-requests-with-github-actions-13f890538e32&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;p>I recently did some work on the mybinder.org deployment infrastructure to solve a problem with testing Pull Requests before deployment.
It had not been possible to test Pull Requests on our staging deployment because our automated workflows don&amp;rsquo;t have access to secrets.
This resulted in my writing the &lt;a href="https://github.com/sgibson91/test-this-pr-action">&lt;code>test-this-pr&lt;/code> action&lt;/a> and this blog is a retrospective of what I learned over that process.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Create a Blog with Hugo and GitHub Pages</title><link>https://sgibson91.github.io/blog/hugo-tutorial/</link><pubDate>Thu, 24 Jun 2021 16:28:20 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://sgibson91.github.io/blog/hugo-tutorial/</guid><description>&lt;p>As a scientist in today&amp;rsquo;s ever connected, digital world, having a platform to talk about one&amp;rsquo;s work can be a really useful tool.
Whether you&amp;rsquo;re looking to strike up new collaborations or promote your freshly published paper, a blog can help signal boost your work and function as an archive of your ideas (the developed and forgotten).&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I put together a tutorial for building a blog site from scratch using &lt;a href="https://gohugo.io/">Hugo&lt;/a> and &lt;a href="https://pages.github.com/">GitHub Pages&lt;/a> - the same tools I use to host this site!&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>