<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>devops on</title><link>https://sgibson91.github.io/tags/devops/</link><description>Recent content in devops on</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-gb</language><lastBuildDate>Mon, 22 Nov 2021 19:35:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://sgibson91.github.io/tags/devops/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>How I automated authorised cloud deployments from Pull Requests with GitHub Actions</title><link>https://sgibson91.github.io/blog/test-this-pr/</link><pubDate>Mon, 22 Nov 2021 19:35:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://sgibson91.github.io/blog/test-this-pr/</guid><description>This blog was originally posted on the Jupyter blog: https://blog.jupyter.org/how-i-automated-authorised-cloud-deployments-from-pull-requests-with-github-actions-13f890538e32
I recently did some work on the mybinder.org deployment infrastructure to solve a problem with testing Pull Requests before deployment. It had not been possible to test Pull Requests on our staging deployment because our automated workflows don&amp;rsquo;t have access to secrets. This resulted in my writing the test-this-pr action and this blog is a retrospective of what I learned over that process.</description></item><item><title>Continuous Integration: Fail Fast and Fail First</title><link>https://sgibson91.github.io/blog/continuous-integration/</link><pubDate>Thu, 27 Feb 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://sgibson91.github.io/blog/continuous-integration/</guid><description>Sarah and Graham have different career backgrounds - Sarah having come through academia whereas Graham earned his stripes in industry. However in their current roles, they often find themselves using the same tools, for example Continuous Integration. They have written this blog post to identify how academia and industry may use Continuous Integration in different ways, and what they might learn from one another.
What is Continuous Integration and why do we use it?</description></item></channel></rss>