<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Update on</title><link>https://sgibson91.github.io/tags/update/</link><description>Recent content in Update on</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en-gb</language><lastBuildDate>Sun, 23 Feb 2020 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://sgibson91.github.io/tags/update/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>February 2020 Update</title><link>https://sgibson91.github.io/blog/february-2020-update/</link><pubDate>Sun, 23 Feb 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://sgibson91.github.io/blog/february-2020-update/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;Hello friends! :wave:
It feels like such a long time since I wrote a blog post but the truth is that I&amp;rsquo;ve just been up to so many exciting things!
So this blog post will be a quick run down on everything I&amp;rsquo;ve been up to recently.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At the start of January, I helped organise and run the &lt;a href="https://research-software-reactor.github.io/"&gt;Research Software Reactor&lt;/a&gt; with &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/ixek"&gt;Tania Allard&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/gerardjgorman"&gt;Gerard Gorman&lt;/a&gt;.
Our topic was &amp;ldquo;&lt;a href="https://research-software-reactor.github.io/blog/devops4rse"&gt;DevOps for better software and research reproducibility&lt;/a&gt;&amp;rdquo;.
We had around 30 attendees come together at the Turing Institute for 2 days and learn about &lt;a href="https://github.com/features/actions"&gt;GitHub Actions&lt;/a&gt; for automating their workflows.
The aim was to produce reproducible software to support gold-standard research.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Software Sustainability Institute Fellowship 2020</title><link>https://sgibson91.github.io/blog/ssi-fellowship/</link><pubDate>Fri, 10 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://sgibson91.github.io/blog/ssi-fellowship/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;So 2020 is off to an incredibly exciting start!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;I have been awarded a Software Sustainability Institute 2020 Fellowship!!!&lt;/strong&gt; :tada: :tada: :tada:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The &lt;a href="https://software.ac.uk"&gt;Software Sustainability Institute&lt;/a&gt; (SSI) is an organisation that facilitates the advancement of software in research by cultivating better, more sustainable, research software to enable world-class research (“Better software, better research”).
Its mission is to become the world-leading hub for research software practice.
The Institute is based at the Universities of Edinburgh, Manchester, Oxford and Southampton, and draws on a team of experts with a breadth of experience in software development, project and programme management, research facilitation, publicity and community engagement.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>2019: Seasons of Reflection</title><link>https://sgibson91.github.io/blog/seasons-of-reflection/</link><pubDate>Thu, 19 Dec 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://sgibson91.github.io/blog/seasons-of-reflection/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;As 2019 comes to a close, I have spent a full year as a Research Software Engineer (RSE) at The Alan Turing Institute.
A lot has changed over the last 12 months and I&amp;rsquo;ve come a long way - sometimes surprising myself!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id="winter-snowflake"&gt;Winter :snowflake:&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In February, I gave my first professional talk at the &lt;a href="https://cloud.ac.uk/workshops/feb2019/"&gt;UKRI Cloud Working Group workshop&lt;/a&gt; hosted by The Francis Crick Institute.
It wasn&amp;rsquo;t the furthest I&amp;rsquo;ve travelled for a conference giving it&amp;rsquo;s next door to the British Library, but it was certainly good practice!&lt;/p&gt;</description></item></channel></rss>