<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Ssi on</title><link>https://sgibson91.github.io/tags/ssi/</link><description>Recent content in Ssi on</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en-gb</language><lastBuildDate>Thu, 15 Apr 2021 19:13:50 +0100</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://sgibson91.github.io/tags/ssi/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Collaborations Workshop 2021</title><link>https://sgibson91.github.io/blog/collabw21/</link><pubDate>Thu, 15 Apr 2021 19:13:50 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://sgibson91.github.io/blog/collabw21/</guid><description>&lt;p>At the end of March 2021, I attended the Collaborations Workshop hosted by the Software Sustainability Institute.
The following is my round-up of what the event is, who runs it, and some of my highlights.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="what-is-the-ssi">What is the SSI?&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>The &lt;a href="https://software.ac.uk/about">Software Sustainability Institute&lt;/a> (SSI for short) is a network of UK universities, Research Software Engineering groups and policy makers dedicated in improving the quality, sustainability and recognition of research software.
They help the members in their network learn software skills and best practices, and advocate for culture change in their organisations and institutions.
I am also an &lt;a href="https://software.ac.uk/programmes-and-events/fellowship-programme">SSI Fellow&lt;/a> and if anyone has any questions about the Fellowship round in the future, please do get in touch (unfortunately, applications have already closed for the 2021 round).
And &lt;a href="https://sgibson91.github.io/blog/ssi-fellowship/" title="Software Sustainability Institute Fellowship 2020">read my previous blog&lt;/a> to find out more about my Fellowship goals.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Software Sustainability Institute Fellowship 2020</title><link>https://sgibson91.github.io/blog/ssi-fellowship/</link><pubDate>Fri, 10 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://sgibson91.github.io/blog/ssi-fellowship/</guid><description>&lt;p>So 2020 is off to an incredibly exciting start!&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>I have been awarded a Software Sustainability Institute 2020 Fellowship!!!&lt;/strong> :tada: :tada: :tada:&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The &lt;a href="https://software.ac.uk">Software Sustainability Institute&lt;/a> (SSI) is an organisation that facilitates the advancement of software in research by cultivating better, more sustainable, research software to enable world-class research (“Better software, better research”).
Its mission is to become the world-leading hub for research software practice.
The Institute is based at the Universities of Edinburgh, Manchester, Oxford and Southampton, and draws on a team of experts with a breadth of experience in software development, project and programme management, research facilitation, publicity and community engagement.&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>