<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>community on</title><link>https://sgibson91.github.io/tags/community/</link><description>Recent content in community on</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-gb</language><lastBuildDate>Fri, 10 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://sgibson91.github.io/tags/community/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Software Sustainability Institute Fellowship 2020</title><link>https://sgibson91.github.io/blog/ssi-fellowship/</link><pubDate>Fri, 10 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://sgibson91.github.io/blog/ssi-fellowship/</guid><description>So 2020 is off to an incredibly exciting start!
I have been awarded a Software Sustainability Institute 2020 Fellowship!!! 🎉 🎉 🎉
We are thrilled to announce the new cohort of @SoftwareSaved Fellows for 2020! You can find out more about the new cohort here: https://t.co/WPTePa3hoP
Congratulations to the SSI Fellows 2020! #SSIFellows2020 #BetterSoftwareBetterResearch pic.twitter.com/zX21yvZo3h
&amp;mdash; The Software Sustainability Institute (@SoftwareSaved) January 10, 2020 The Software Sustainability Institute (SSI) is an organisation that facilitates the advancement of software in research by cultivating better, more sustainable, research software to enable world-class research (“Better software, better research”).</description></item><item><title>Binder</title><link>https://sgibson91.github.io/project/binder/</link><pubDate>Sun, 31 Mar 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://sgibson91.github.io/project/binder/</guid><description>Binder is a project that allows users to create custom computing environments that can be shared and used by many remote users. It is powered by BinderHub, which is an open-source tool that deploys the Binder service in the cloud.
One such Binder service is mybinder.org and is free to use. More information about mybinder.org and the team that runs is can be found on the &amp;ldquo;About mybinder.org&amp;rdquo; page.
As a member of the Binder operating team, Sarah&amp;rsquo;s role involves maintaining the mybinder.</description></item><item><title>The Turing Way</title><link>https://sgibson91.github.io/project/turing-way/</link><pubDate>Mon, 31 Dec 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://sgibson91.github.io/project/turing-way/</guid><description>The Turing Way is an online handbook - and global community - dedicated to fostering gold-standard reproducible research.
It&amp;rsquo;s a cultural movement with the potential to transform data science.
There is a crisis of reproducibility in science. &amp;lsquo;Publish-or-perish&amp;rsquo; incentives and excessive data secrecy stifles progress and wastes resources: siloed science is slow science.
The Turing Way is an evolving online &amp;lsquo;handbook&amp;rsquo; on how to conduct world-leading, reproducible research in academic data science and AI with the goal of making reproducible science &amp;ldquo;too easy not to do&amp;rdquo;.</description></item></channel></rss>