<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Blogs on</title><link>https://sgibson91.github.io/blog/</link><description>Recent content in Blogs on</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-gb</language><lastBuildDate>Thu, 12 May 2022 11:51:52 +0100</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://sgibson91.github.io/blog/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Tech update: Multiple JupyterHubs, multiple clusters, one repository.</title><link>https://sgibson91.github.io/blog/2i2c-ci-cd-improvements/</link><pubDate>Thu, 12 May 2022 11:51:52 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://sgibson91.github.io/blog/2i2c-ci-cd-improvements/</guid><description>This blog was originally posted by 2i2c and represents a project Sarah lead and developed.
2i2c manages the configuration and deployment of multiple Kubernetes clusters and JupyterHubs from a single open infrastructure repository. This is a challenging problem, as it requires us to centralize information about a number of independent cloud services, and deploy them in an efficient and reliable manner. Our initial attempt at this had a number of inefficiencies, and we recently completed an overhaul of its configuration and deployment infrastructure.</description></item><item><title>Things I've Learned: January 2022</title><link>https://sgibson91.github.io/blog/til-jan22/</link><pubDate>Mon, 31 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://sgibson91.github.io/blog/til-jan22/</guid><description>An Unordered Collection of Things I Learn over a Month</description></item><item><title>How I automated authorised cloud deployments from Pull Requests with GitHub Actions</title><link>https://sgibson91.github.io/blog/test-this-pr/</link><pubDate>Mon, 22 Nov 2021 19:35:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://sgibson91.github.io/blog/test-this-pr/</guid><description>This blog was originally posted on the Jupyter blog: https://blog.jupyter.org/how-i-automated-authorised-cloud-deployments-from-pull-requests-with-github-actions-13f890538e32
I recently did some work on the mybinder.org deployment infrastructure to solve a problem with testing Pull Requests before deployment. It had not been possible to test Pull Requests on our staging deployment because our automated workflows don&amp;rsquo;t have access to secrets. This resulted in my writing the test-this-pr action and this blog is a retrospective of what I learned over that process.</description></item><item><title>Create a Blog with Hugo and GitHub Pages</title><link>https://sgibson91.github.io/blog/hugo-tutorial/</link><pubDate>Thu, 24 Jun 2021 16:28:20 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://sgibson91.github.io/blog/hugo-tutorial/</guid><description>As a scientist in today&amp;rsquo;s ever connected, digital world, having a platform to talk about one&amp;rsquo;s work can be a really useful tool. Whether you&amp;rsquo;re looking to strike up new collaborations or promote your freshly published paper, a blog can help signal boost your work and function as an archive of your ideas (the developed and forgotten).
I put together a tutorial for building a blog site from scratch using Hugo and GitHub Pages - the same tools I use to host this site!</description></item><item><title>Collaborations Workshop 2021</title><link>https://sgibson91.github.io/blog/collabw21/</link><pubDate>Thu, 15 Apr 2021 19:13:50 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://sgibson91.github.io/blog/collabw21/</guid><description>A Summary of #CollabW21</description></item><item><title>Continuous Integration: Fail Fast and Fail First</title><link>https://sgibson91.github.io/blog/continuous-integration/</link><pubDate>Thu, 27 Feb 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://sgibson91.github.io/blog/continuous-integration/</guid><description>How to industry and academia take advantage of shared tools</description></item><item><title>February 2020 Update</title><link>https://sgibson91.github.io/blog/february-2020-update/</link><pubDate>Sun, 23 Feb 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://sgibson91.github.io/blog/february-2020-update/</guid><description>Hello friends! 👋 It feels like such a long time since I wrote a blog post but the truth is that I&amp;rsquo;ve just been up to so many exciting things! So this blog post will be a quick run down on everything I&amp;rsquo;ve been up to recently.
At the start of January, I helped organise and run the Research Software Reactor with Tania Allard and Gerard Gorman. Our topic was &amp;ldquo;DevOps for better software and research reproducibility&amp;rdquo;.</description></item><item><title>Software Sustainability Institute Fellowship 2020</title><link>https://sgibson91.github.io/blog/ssi-fellowship/</link><pubDate>Fri, 10 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://sgibson91.github.io/blog/ssi-fellowship/</guid><description>So 2020 is off to an incredibly exciting start!
I have been awarded a Software Sustainability Institute 2020 Fellowship!!! 🎉 🎉 🎉
We are thrilled to announce the new cohort of @SoftwareSaved Fellows for 2020! You can find out more about the new cohort here: https://t.co/WPTePa3hoP
Congratulations to the SSI Fellows 2020! #SSIFellows2020 #BetterSoftwareBetterResearch pic.twitter.com/zX21yvZo3h
&amp;mdash; The Software Sustainability Institute (@SoftwareSaved) January 10, 2020 The Software Sustainability Institute (SSI) is an organisation that facilitates the advancement of software in research by cultivating better, more sustainable, research software to enable world-class research (“Better software, better research”).</description></item><item><title>2019: Seasons of Reflection</title><link>https://sgibson91.github.io/blog/seasons-of-reflection/</link><pubDate>Thu, 19 Dec 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://sgibson91.github.io/blog/seasons-of-reflection/</guid><description>As 2019 comes to a close, I have spent a full year as a Research Software Engineer (RSE) at The Alan Turing Institute. A lot has changed over the last 12 months and I&amp;rsquo;ve come a long way - sometimes surprising myself!
Winter ❄️ In February, I gave my first professional talk at the UKRI Cloud Working Group workshop hosted by The Francis Crick Institute. It wasn&amp;rsquo;t the furthest I&amp;rsquo;ve travelled for a conference giving it&amp;rsquo;s next door to the British Library, but it was certainly good practice!</description></item><item><title>Diving Into Leadership to Build Push-Button Code</title><link>https://sgibson91.github.io/blog/diving-into-leadership/</link><pubDate>Thu, 17 Oct 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://sgibson91.github.io/blog/diving-into-leadership/</guid><description>Sarah's experiences at the Microsoft Reactor Sprint 2019</description></item></channel></rss>