<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Binder on</title><link>https://sgibson91.github.io/tags/binder/</link><description>Recent content in Binder on</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en-gb</language><lastBuildDate>Mon, 22 Nov 2021 19:35:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://sgibson91.github.io/tags/binder/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>How I automated authorised cloud deployments from Pull Requests with GitHub Actions</title><link>https://sgibson91.github.io/blog/test-this-pr/</link><pubDate>Mon, 22 Nov 2021 19:35:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://sgibson91.github.io/blog/test-this-pr/</guid><description>&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This blog was originally posted on the Jupyter blog: &lt;a href="https://blog.jupyter.org/how-i-automated-authorised-cloud-deployments-from-pull-requests-with-github-actions-13f890538e32"&gt;https://blog.jupyter.org/how-i-automated-authorised-cloud-deployments-from-pull-requests-with-github-actions-13f890538e32&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I recently did some work on the mybinder.org deployment infrastructure to solve a problem with testing Pull Requests before deployment.
It had not been possible to test Pull Requests on our staging deployment because our automated workflows don&amp;rsquo;t have access to secrets.
This resulted in my writing the &lt;a href="https://github.com/sgibson91/test-this-pr-action"&gt;&lt;code&gt;test-this-pr&lt;/code&gt; action&lt;/a&gt; and this blog is a retrospective of what I learned over that process.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Software Sustainability Institute Fellowship 2020</title><link>https://sgibson91.github.io/blog/ssi-fellowship/</link><pubDate>Fri, 10 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://sgibson91.github.io/blog/ssi-fellowship/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;So 2020 is off to an incredibly exciting start!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;I have been awarded a Software Sustainability Institute 2020 Fellowship!!!&lt;/strong&gt; :tada: :tada: :tada:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The &lt;a href="https://software.ac.uk"&gt;Software Sustainability Institute&lt;/a&gt; (SSI) is an organisation that facilitates the advancement of software in research by cultivating better, more sustainable, research software to enable world-class research (“Better software, better research”).
Its mission is to become the world-leading hub for research software practice.
The Institute is based at the Universities of Edinburgh, Manchester, Oxford and Southampton, and draws on a team of experts with a breadth of experience in software development, project and programme management, research facilitation, publicity and community engagement.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Diving Into Leadership to Build Push-Button Code</title><link>https://sgibson91.github.io/blog/diving-into-leadership/</link><pubDate>Thu, 17 Oct 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://sgibson91.github.io/blog/diving-into-leadership/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&amp;ldquo;Hi everyone, I&amp;rsquo;m Sarah! I&amp;rsquo;m a Research Data Scientist at the Alan Turing Institute and I&amp;rsquo;m also an operator of mybinder.org. It&amp;rsquo;s really cool seeing how many people here are interested in BinderHub!&amp;rdquo;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And it is cool. &lt;em&gt;Really&lt;/em&gt; cool! But also a bit scary as a room full of Research Software Engineers (each of them much further on in their careers than I am) suddenly turn to me, eager for the knowledge I was surely about to impart to them.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item></channel></rss>