<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>continuous-integration on</title><link>https://sgibson91.github.io/tags/continuous-integration/</link><description>Recent content in continuous-integration on</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-gb</language><lastBuildDate>Mon, 22 Nov 2021 19:35:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://sgibson91.github.io/tags/continuous-integration/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>How I automated authorised cloud deployments from Pull Requests with GitHub Actions</title><link>https://sgibson91.github.io/blog/test-this-pr/</link><pubDate>Mon, 22 Nov 2021 19:35:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://sgibson91.github.io/blog/test-this-pr/</guid><description>This blog was originally posted on the Jupyter blog: https://blog.jupyter.org/how-i-automated-authorised-cloud-deployments-from-pull-requests-with-github-actions-13f890538e32
I recently did some work on the mybinder.org deployment infrastructure to solve a problem with testing Pull Requests before deployment. It had not been possible to test Pull Requests on our staging deployment because our automated workflows don&amp;rsquo;t have access to secrets. This resulted in my writing the test-this-pr action and this blog is a retrospective of what I learned over that process.</description></item><item><title>Create a Blog with Hugo and GitHub Pages</title><link>https://sgibson91.github.io/blog/hugo-tutorial/</link><pubDate>Thu, 24 Jun 2021 16:28:20 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://sgibson91.github.io/blog/hugo-tutorial/</guid><description>As a scientist in today&amp;rsquo;s ever connected, digital world, having a platform to talk about one&amp;rsquo;s work can be a really useful tool. Whether you&amp;rsquo;re looking to strike up new collaborations or promote your freshly published paper, a blog can help signal boost your work and function as an archive of your ideas (the developed and forgotten).
I put together a tutorial for building a blog site from scratch using Hugo and GitHub Pages - the same tools I use to host this site!</description></item><item><title>Continuous Integration: Fail Fast and Fail First</title><link>https://sgibson91.github.io/blog/continuous-integration/</link><pubDate>Thu, 27 Feb 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://sgibson91.github.io/blog/continuous-integration/</guid><description>How to industry and academia take advantage of shared tools</description></item></channel></rss>